Guide to the Bruce Kellner Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Bruce Kellner papers
1929-2003
1952-2000
YCAL MSS 709
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.73
(9 boxes)
The Bruce Kellner Papers consist of letters to Kellner and other papers, including two poems by Fania Marinoff, actress and wife of Carl Van Vechten, a list of Marinoff's appearances on stage and in films, and a portion of Marinoff's last will and testament. Correspondents include Donald Gallup, Carl Van Vechten, Alice B. Toklas, Donald Windham, Fania Marinoff, Donald Angus, and others.
Kellner, Bruce, 1930-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Bruce and Margaret Kellner, 1989-2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Bruce Kellner
Bruce Kellner, American author and Harlem Renaissance scholar.
Scope and Contents
The Bruce Kellner Papers consist of letters to Kellner and other papers, including two poems by Fania Marinoff, actress and wife of Carl Van Vechten, a list of Marinoff's appearances on stage and in films, and a portion of Marinoff's last will and testament. Correspondents include Donald Gallup, Carl Van Vechten, Alice B. Toklas, Donald Windham, Fania Marinoff, Donald Angus, and others.
Arrangement
Organized into eight groupings: I. 1989 Acquisition, 1929-1964. II. 1991 Acquisition, 1951-1961. III. 1993 Acquisition, 1956-1964. IV. 1994 Acquisition, 1952-1963. V. 2000 Acquisitions, 1959-1975. VI. 2001 Acquisition, 1952-2000. VII. 2007 Acquisition, 1967-2000. VIII. 2008 Acquisition, 1984-2003.
African American authors -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Harlem Renaissance; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Angus, Donald; Gallup, Donald, 1913-2000; Kellner, Bruce, 1930-; Marinoff, Fania, 1890-1971; Toklas, Alice B., 1877-1967; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; Windham, Donald
- 1989 Acquisition, 1929-1964, undated; 1; 0.21; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 88
  - Correspondence
    - Angus, Donald, 1932-1959 (Box 1)
    - Jepson, William, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
    - Lutz, John Mark, 1943, undated (Box 1)
    - Lutz, Mary, 1938-1948 (Box 1)
    - Marchant, Peter, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Moses, Elliott, 1942 (Box 1)
    - Rutledge, Richard, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
    - Storm, Leah Maynard, 1929, 1939, undated (Box 1)
- 1991 Acquisition, 1951-1964; 2; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 192
  - Letters from Carl Van Vechten to Kellner, 1951-1961; 12 (Box 2)
  - Letters from Carl Van Vechten to Kellner, 1962-1964; 3 (Box 3)
- 1993 Acquisition, 1956-1964; 3
  Former call number: Uncat ZA File 297
  - Three autograph notes signed; two typed letters signed; and one autograph letter signed to Richard Rutledge from Carl Van Vechten, 1956-1964 (Box 3)
- 1994 Acquisition, 1952-1963; 4; 0.21; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 407
  - Letters from Alice B. Toklas to Kellner, 1952-1963; 2 (Box 4)
- 2000 Acquisitions, 1959-1975, undated; 5; 0.21; (1 box)
  Former call numbers: Uncat MSS 35 and Uncat ZA File 411
  - Correspondence
    - Lutz, Mark, 1965 (Box 5)
    - Jepsen, William, 1968 July (Box 5)
    - Marinoff, Fania (Fania Marinoff Van Vechten), 1959-1971; 3 (Box 5)
    - Marinoff, Nathan, 1965 (Box 5)
    - Wallace, Reggie, circa 1968-1975 (Box 5)
  - Other Papers
    - Untitled poem by Fania Marinoff, autograph manuscript sent to Donald Angus, 1975 June 17 (Box 5)
    - 'To Carlo," typescript poem by Marinoff, 1967 June (Box 5)
    - "A Partial List of Fania Marinoff's Appearances on Stage and in Films," typescript, undated (Box 5)
    - Marinoff's Last Will and Testament, listing beneficiaries, 1971 November 26 (Box 5)
    - Twenty recipes belonging to Carl Van Vechten and Fania Marinoff with two manuscript notes, undated (Box 5)
      Former call number: Uncat ZA File 411
- 2001 Acquisition, 1952-2000; 6; 0.21; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 110
  - Letters from Donald Gallup to Bruce Kellner, 1952-2000; 23 (Box 6)
- 2007 Acquisition, 1967-2000; 7; 0.42; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 971
  Kellner wrote and enclosed a note with each group of correspondence, describing the individual's personality and their relationship.
  - Correspondence
    - Angus, Donald, 1979-1988, undated; 2 (Box 7)
    - George, George, 1979-1982; 2 (Box 7)
    - Lueders, Edward, 1971-2000; 2 (Box 7)
    - Lutz, Mark and William Jepson, 1967-1981 (Box 7)
    - Taylor, Prentiss, 1982-1986 (Box 7)
- 2008 Acquisition, 1984-2003, undated; 8; 0.84; (2 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1039
  - Correspondence
    - Burns, Edward, 1987-1998 (Box 8)
    - Dydo, Ulla, 1992-1998 (Box 8)
    - Haas, Robert Bartlett, 1990-1995 (Box 8)
    - Rampersaa, Arnold, 1984-1993 (Box 8)
    - Watson, Steven, 1993-2001 (Box 8)
    - Wilson, Robert A., 1999-2007, undated (Box 8)
    - Windham, Donald, 1985-2000, undated; 2 (Box 8)
    - Windham, Donald, 1985-2003, undated; 2 (Box 9)
    - Various correspondents, 2 (Box 9)